empivot.com 2010-11-20

# emPivot Company Blog | The Online Network for Green Video » Privacy Policy

In addition to providing a video sharing service and search engine related to green-related media, emPivot.com provides a service that allows our members to set up unique personal profiles and channels that can be linked together through networks of friends. emPivot members are able to view each others’ profiles, communicate with businesses and make new connections, share videos, post comments and describe their interests. As part of this service, it is required that we request and display some personal information to other members and visitors. This allows us to promote this community capability and enable our members to grow their connections. emPivot members are able to modify and change their profile information at any time and can control how other members and the emPivot generates communications to their account.

emPivot.com takes privacy very seriously. We know you might have questions, so when you have one regarding this privacy policy, please email us at privacy[at]emPivot.com.

**How We Collect and Use Information for emPivot.com**  
Certain functions of emPivot.com require that we collect user submitted information such as user name, password, name, and email address to authenticate users and to send notifications to users about the emPivot.com service. emPivot.com also collects other profile data through its voluntary user submitted areas, including but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, education and occupation for the purpose of broadening the ability of our community to connect.

emPivot.com also records and logs non-personally-identifiable information including profile information, aggregate user data, IP address, and browser type from members and visitors on the site. We use this information to best serve your interest and security. This data is used to manage the website, track usage and improve the emPivot.com website services. This is very generic information and is not identifiable at the individual level, and therefore we may share this information with third-parties to develop relevant services and advertisements for members. We do monitor User IP addresses for security and monitoring purposes.

**How We Display Your Information Publicly**  
When you become a member of emPivot.com, parts of your profile information will become public. This information if filled in fully includes: a member’s profile picture, name, and geographic location. We display this information to provide for an informed user interaction in the emPivot community.

**  
Email Addresses: Contacting and Inviting Your Friends to emPivot**  
emPivot makes it easy for members to invite friends not signed up at emPivot.com to join our video sharing and community service by sending an invitation emails via our invitation system. We do not store or use the information of the person who received the invitation.

emPivot members will store other emPivot members’ user names, not their email addresses within their member contact list. Through this function, members can send other members and invitations and other communications, which will be delivered via emPivot to that members inbox at emPivot. If a member has their preferences set to notify the member of new communication, that correspondence will be forwarded to the receiving member’s email by way of emPivot and the other member will not have access to that email address.

A user’s email address is not shared or displayed to people within a user’s personal network. User names are revealed as the primary identifier for an identity on the site. However, the Name field from the profile is shown on the profile page. If you do not wish to share your full name, please modify your name field for your comfort level. To facilitate searching and finding friends and acquaintances on the service, emPivot allows users to search for other members using first and last name, email address, and schools and/or companies where users may have attended or worked.

If you have opted into newsletter services we will send you updates and newsletters to your email address. All users are subject to receiving basic service updates from the emPivot.com service. Within the My Account > Notifications area members may toggle on and off their receive email settings for various communications of emPivot.com.

**Use of Cookies**  
emPivot uses cookies to heighten the experience of emPivot Users. For example, cookies are implored to ensure that visitors not receive the same advertisements as they explore sub-pages. Also, emPivot uses cookies to customize newsletters and web page Content based on user profile information and browser types. Personal identifiable information that you submit while on emPivot is not used as cookies. Ideally, emPivot asks users to allow cookies while on the emPivot website.

**Links**  
emPivot allows links to other 3rd party websites. emPivot is not responsible for User disseminating personal information on such links. These links in question range from chat rooms, journals and web logs, message boards, classifieds and public forums. emPivot is not responsible for the private policies and/or practices on other site. If a user links to a 3rd party website, emPivot strongly encourages users to read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy is limited to, and governs, information collected on emPivot.

**Correcting/Updating or Removing Information  
**emPivot reserves the right to alter or remove any personal information without notice in order to preserve the integrity of the site. For more information on this policy, please see emPivot’s Terms of Service.

emPivot member accounts are secured by member-created passwords. emPivot aggressively works to ensure member account information remains private. We review our database daily and we restrict access to only a few employees authorized to view such confidential information. emPivot does not guarantee the security of member account information. Security breaches, unauthorized entry or use, software and hardware failure do happen. Please take precautions to secure your personal information.

**Sharing and Disclosure of Information EmPivot Collects**  
Except noted in this privacy statement, emPivot will not disclose personal information to 3rd parties unless we believe disclosure is necessary. Full disclosure will occur when: (1) emPivot is subpoenaed, provided a search warrant or other legal processes, whether or not an emPivot response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce emPivot’s Terms of Service agreement; (3) to protect the safety our community and users of our Service.

**Changes in Our Privacy Policy  
** Changes to our private policy occur periodically. We ask that users review the private policy daily in order to stay current. A user is bound by the emPivot Terms of Service and the private policy once he/she enters the site. If emPivot users personal information to accent such changes, we will notify the user prior. ****

****Contacting the Web Site  
****If you have any questions of concerns about emPivot’s privacy policy, please contact us at privacy[at]empivot.com.
